Guide to the Michael Polanyi Papers 1900-1975
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Manuscripts
  - Subseries 17: 1953
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Review of F. A. Hayek, The Counter-Revolution of Science The Determinants of Social Action (revised) Review of Robert Strauz-Hupé, The Estrangement of Western Man Protests and Problems Review of Bernard Barber, Science and the Social Order Review of Jules Monnerat, Sociology of Communism Soziale Illusionen (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 18: 1954
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Review of Arthur Koestler, Invisible Writing Review of Ralph Barton Perry, Realms of Value Review of J. Robert Oppenheimer, Science and the Common Understanding Review of A. J. H. Sprott, Science and Social Action (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 19: 1955, 1956, 1957
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Review of Gabriel A. Almond, The Appeals of Communism (1955) From Copernicus to Einstein (1955) The Future of Liberalism in Eastern Europe (1957) Hydrogen Bomb (1957) The Magic of Marxism (1956) On the Limits of Economic Planning (1955) Social Control: Visible and Invisible (1957) Review of V. G. Childe, Society and Knowledge (1956) Study Group of the Committee for Science and Freedom (1956) Die Stunde der Wahrheit (1956) This Age of Discovery (1956) Words, Conceptions and Science (1955) (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 20: 1958
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, The Outlook of Science: Its Sickness and Cure Positive Liberalism (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Das Studium des Menschen (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 21: 1959
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts and untitled manuscripts, Questions for an Inquiry into the Nature of Soviet Planning "I would like to say that..." "The ideas which I want to sketch here..." (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 22: 1960
    - Perspectives of Personal Knowledge, The Gunning Lectures, Lecture 1, "Logical Foundations" (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Perspectives of Personal Knowledge, Lecture 2, "Originality" (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Perspectives of Personal Knowledge, Lecture 3, "Emergence and Reflection" (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Perspectives of Personal Knowledge, Lecture 4, "Social Structure and Alienation, Commitment" (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Perspectives of Personal Knowledge, Lecture 5, "The Process of History" (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes Beyond Nihilism (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes Beyond Nihilism (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Review of Pierre Teilhard de Chardin, The Phenomenon of Man Rede von Professor Michael Polanyi auf der Schlusssitzung The Study of Man Theory of Conspicuous Productions (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Originality (revised) (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Personal Judgment in Science (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Science, Academic and Industrial (revised) (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Science and Reality (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - St. Julians, March 1960 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - The Structure of Tacit Knowing (early draft) (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 23: 1961
    - History and Hope, lectures delivered at the Thomas Jefferson Center for studies in political economy at the University of Virginia (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Beyond Nihilism, A Postscript (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 24: 1962
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Conspicuous Production (revised) My Time with X-Rays and Crystals (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects (the stage of 11 May 1962), Chapter 2, "The Realm of the Unspoken" (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 3, "The Vindication of Reality" (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 4, "Emergence" (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 5, "A Society of Explorers" (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 6, "Commitment" (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Terry Lectures as delivered at Yale University, October 31-November 3, 1962, (Much of this material was revised for the 1964 Duke University Lectures) Lecture 1, first half, "Tacit Knowing" (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Terry Lectures as delivered at Yale University, Lecture 1, first half, "Tacit Knowing" (with 1963 revisions) (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Terry Lectures as delivered at Yale University, Lecture 1, first half, "Tacit Knowing" (with 1963 revisions) (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Terry Lectures as delivered at Yale University, Lecture 1, first half, "Tacit Knowing" (with 1963 revisions) (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Terry Lectures as delivered at Yale University, Lecture 1, part 2, "Tacit Knowing: Heuristics" (1963 revision) (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Terry Lectures as delivered at Yale University, Lecture 2, "Comprehensive Entities" (with 1963 revision entitled, "Emergence") (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Terry Lectures as delivered at Yale University, Lecture 3, "Man in Thought" (with 1963 revision entitled, "Thought in Society") (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 25: 1963
    - Tacit Knowing (a version of the first Terry Lecture revised for publication) (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Tacit Knowing (a version of the first Terry Lecture revised for publication) (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - The Metaphysical Aspects of Science (early draft) (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - The Metaphysical Reach of Science (early draft) (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - The Metaphysical Reach of Science (early draft) (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Points from a Conversation with Paul Tillich (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 26: 1964
    - Man in Thought, lectures delivered at Duke University, Lecture 1, "The Metaphysical Reach of Science" (lecture copy) (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 1, "The Metaphysical Reach of Science" Mimeograph and carbon copies (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 1, "The Metaphysical Reach of Science" Corrected carbons (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 1, "The Metaphysical Reach of Science" Adapted to book format (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 1, "The Metaphysical Reach of Science" Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 2, "The Structure of Tacit Knowing" Two copies used in lecture (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 2, "The Structure of Tacit Knowing" Mimeograph and carbon copies (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 2, "The Structure of Tacit Knowing" As delivered in Chicago, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 2, "The Structure of Tacit Knowing" Adapted to book format (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 3, "Commitment to Science" Copy used in lecture (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 3, "Commitment to Science" Mimeograph copies (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 3, "Commitment to Science" Adapted to book format (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 4, "The Emergence of Man" Copy used in lecture (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 4, "The Emergence of Man" Mimeograph copies (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 5, "Thought in Society" Copy used in lecture (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 5, "Thought in Society" Mimeograph copies (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Man in Thought, Lecture 5, "Thought in Society" Adapted to book format (entitled, "Chapter 3, The Powers of the Imagination") (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Notes for a projected sixth Duke Lecture on "Ultimate Reality" (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects (1964 revision) Chapter 1, "The Destruction of Reality" (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 2, "The Realm of the Unspoken" (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 3, "The Vindication of Reality" (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 4, "Emergence" (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 5, "A Society of Explorers" (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Chapter 6, "Commitment" (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Lecture delivered at Bowdoin College (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts and untitled manuscripts, About Religious Faith Grounds of Knowledge Modern Minds-New Departures Notes to Ultimate Reality On Body and Mind Tacit Affiliations "Let me explore this vision..." (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Science, Tacit and Explicit (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 27: 1965
    - The Body-Mind Relation (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Wesleyan Lectures, Lecture 1, "Science and Reality" (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Lecture 2, "The Structure of Tacit Knowing" (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Lecture 3, "The Creative Imagination," (also entitled "Man in Thought," and "Powers of the Imagination") (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Lecture 3, "The Creative Imagination," (also entitled "Man in Thought," and "Powers of the Imagination") (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Lecture 4, "The Growth of Science in Society," and Lecture 5, "Levels of Reality" (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - The Modern Mind; Its Structure and Prospects, Bound copy of six lectures (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Man in Search of Meaning (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 28: 1966
    - The Growth of Science in Society (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Autobiography by Michael Polanyi (for Mid-Century Authors) Collection of Data on Cultural Development The Message of the Hungarian Revolution Opening Address, Niebuhr Celebration, New York, Feb 25, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Sinngebung and Sinndeutung (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 29: 1967
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, On the Structure of Living Things Sense-Giving and Sense Reading, Of Language Sixty Years in Universities What is a Painting? (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 30: 1968
    - The Grounds of Knowledge and Discovery, Manuscript and notes (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Logic and Psychology (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - The Meaning of Paintings (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, About Revolutions Already Forgotten Life's Irreducible Structure (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Seminars in the Committee on Social Thought, the University of Chicago, Spring, 1968, Bound copy (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 31: 1969
    - Grounds of Knowledge (Heidelburg revision) (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Grounds of Knowledge (1973 and 1974 revisions) (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Meaning, A Project, Lectures and seminars at the University of Chicago, Lecture 1, "From Perception to Metaphor" (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Meaning, A Project, Lecture 2, "Works of Art" (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Meaning, A Project, Lecture 2, "Works of Art," notes (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Meaning, A Project, Lecture 2, "Works of Art," notes (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Meaning, A Project, Lecture 3, "Visionary Art" (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Meaning, A Project, Lecture 4, "Myths, Ancient and Modern" (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Meaning, A Project, Supplemental materials (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Meaning, a book adapted from Chicago materials by Michael Polanyi and Harry Prosch, Outline and Chapters 1-3 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Meaning, Chapters 4-9 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Meaning, Chapters 10-13 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Meaning, Copy Two, Chapters 1-3 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Meaning, Copy Two, Chapters 4-8 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Meaning, Copy Two, Chapters 9-13 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Meaning, Fragments (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Meaning, bound copy of seminars given in the Committee on Social Thought, the University of Chicago, Spring, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 32: 1970
    - Meaning, Draft of a lecture dated May 1970 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Meaning, Draft of a lecture dated May 1970 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Science and Man, Nuffield Lecture also delivered at Loyola University of Chicago (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 33: 1971
    - Lectures delivered at the University of Texas at Austin, Lecture 1, "Science and Man," (revised version of Nuffield and Loyola lectures) (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Lectures delivered at the University of Texas at Austin, Lecture 2, "Genius in Science" (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Lectures delivered at the University of Texas at Austin, Lecture 2, "Genius in Science" (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Lectures delivered at the University of Texas at Austin, Lecture 3, "Representative Art" (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Lectures delivered at the University of Texas at Austin, Lecture 3, "Representative Art" (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Lectures delivered at the University of Texas at Austin, Lecture 4, "Meaning," and Lecture 5, "Expanding the Range" (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - The Grounds of Natural Science (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 34: 1972
    - About Religious Faith (revised manuscript with notes) (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 35: Undated
    - Untitled essays written between 1935 and 1940 on various subjects (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Untitled essays written between 1935 and 1940 on various subjects (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Untitled essays written between 1935 and 1940 on various subjects (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Untitled essays written between 1935 and 1940 on various subjects (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Clues towards an Understanding of Mind and Body and a Cycle of History (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Discoveries of Science (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Emergence (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Foundations of Science and Discovery (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Honor and Mutual Authority (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Lines of Thought (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Meaning (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Science and Reality (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Part 1 of a presentation on economic productivity (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Part 1 of a presentation on economic productivity (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Fragments (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Fragments (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - German scientific manuscripts (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - German scientific manuscripts (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Speeches of introduction and thanks (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Patents (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Laboratory financial expenditures (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Poetry (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - German translation of Personal Knowledge (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - German translation of Personal Knowledge (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - German translation of Personal Knowledge (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - German translation of Personal Knowledge (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - German translation of Personal Knowledge (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - German translation of Personal Knowledge (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - German translation of Personal Knowledge (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 36: Notebooks, Travel Diaries, and Bibliographies
    - Notebook, Summer, 1926 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Notebook, 1925-1928 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Notebook, "Trip to America," 1929 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Diary-1929 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, "Berlin Visit," Nov 27-Dec 3, 1947 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Notebook, various subjects (undated) (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Notebook containing undated obsolete index to correspondence files (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Notebook, "Books and Papers Lent Out to Fellow Workers"; Notebook, Notes, Aug-Oct 1963, mainly about Dewey (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Bibliographic Citations (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Bibliographic Citations (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Bibliographic Citations (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Bibliographic Citations (Box 44, Folder 12)
- Series IV: Offprints and Memorabilia
  Memorabilia in the Polanyi Papers falls into five groups: photographs and postcards; personal materials (addresses, announcements, Christmas cards, invitations, obituaries, programs, receipts, reports, etc.); miscellaneous clippings and multi-media; offprints by Michael Polanyi; and offprints by other authors and other secondary published works, including photocopied records of Polanyi's collection of books.
  The photographs are of Michael Polanyi, his family and friends. If known, the name of the subject is indicated on the back of the print. The clippings include letters and articles by Michael Polanyi, as well as reviews of Polanyi's work, dissertations which address Polanyi's thought, and articles by Polanyi's mother Cecile (mostly copies of her fashion column in a Budapest newspaper). Other items include a small group of clippings and other printed materials from the German National Socialist period, as well as taped and filmed interviews with Polanyi. This collection also holds offprints and some privately distributed lecture material by Michael Polanyi. Offprints by other authors which remain in this collection have been annotated by Polanyi, or bear holograph inscriptions by their original authors. Finally, this collection holds six volumes of bound photocopies of the title pages of the books in Polanyi's collection, which were dispersed in 1994.
  - Subseries 1: Photographs and Postcards
    - Photographs (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Photographs (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Photographs (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Postcards (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook of photographs, Conference at Mont Pélerin, April 1947 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: General Memorabilia
    - Addresses (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Announcements (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Announcements (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Christmas cards (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Christmas cards (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Invitations (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Obituaries (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Programs (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Receipts (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Reports (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 3: Clippings
    - Letters and articles by Michael Polanyi (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Reviews of Michael Polanyi's work (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of Michael Polanyi's work (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Articles about Michael Polanyi (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Articles concerning the withholding of Michael Polanyi's visa under the McCarran Act (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Articles by Cecile Polanyi (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Articles by Cecile Polanyi (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Articles by Cecile Polanyi (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Articles by Cecile Polanyi (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Printed materials from the German National Socialist period (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Printed materials from the German National Socialist period (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Elizabeth Sewell, Memoir of Michael Polanyi (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Elizabeth Sewell, "Three Tales of Love and Death," typescript, and various poems, typescripts, 1956-1970 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Sam Watson, Jr., "Michael Polanyi; A Grounding for Inventional Theory in Contemporary Rhetoric," dissertation prospectus, 1972 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Paul Wilczak, dissertation prospectus for research on Michael Polanyi, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Paul Wilczak, "Science, Faith, and Human Motivation; An Interpretation of the Thought of Michael Polanyi," Ph.D dissertation (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Reel-to-reel tape recording of interview with Michael Polanyi (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Reel-to-reel tape (contents unknown) (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Microfilm roll of prints by Michael Polanyi, deposited at the Library of Duke University, North Carolina (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Michael Polanyi, "Our Daily Work," (film script) 1935 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Michael Polanyi, 1935/36 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Michael Polanyi, 1936, with related correspondence (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Videotape copy of film, Unemployment and Money, 1938, This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4: Offprints, works by Michael Polanyi
    - 1914-1935 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - 1935-1941 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - 1942-1944 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - 1945 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - 1951 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - 1952-1955 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - 1956-1958 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - 1961 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - 1964 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 1964 (International Congress for Logic, Methodology, and Philosophy of Science, Jerusalem, 1964, Program and Abstracts) (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - 1968 (Materials used in four seminars held by Michael Polanyi, University of Chicago, Spring 1968) (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - 1969-1974 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 5: Offprints by Other Authors
    - A (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - C (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - D (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - E (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - F (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - G (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - H (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - I (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - J (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - K (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - L (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - M (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - M, cont. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - N (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - O-P (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - P (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - P, cont. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Q-R (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - S (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - S, cont. (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - T (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - V (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - W (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Z (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 6: Michael Polanyi Library, photocopied title pages of Polanyi’s library, dispersed July 1994
    - Unnumbered, and nos. 1-100 (Box 57, Volume 1)
    - nos. 101-399 (Box 57, Volume 2)
    - nos. 400-699 (Box 57, Volume 3)
    - nos. 700-954 (Box 57, Volume 4)
    - Unnumbered volumes (Box 58, Volume 5)
    - Unnumbered volumes (Box 58, Volume 6)
    - Film reel, Les Matinées de Michael Polanyi, (Savants IV) (oversize) (Reel 1)
    - Five demonstration posters of the Ptolemaic and Copernican versions of the solar system (evidently derived from Polanyi's chapter, "Science and Reality," in Science, Faith and Society, 1946) (oversize) (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Five demonstration posters of the Ptolemaic and Copernican versions of the solar system (evidently derived from Polanyi's chapter, "Science and Reality," in Science, Faith and Society, 1946) (oversize) (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Five demonstration posters of the Ptolemaic and Copernican versions of the solar system (evidently derived from Polanyi's chapter, "Science and Reality," in Science, Faith and Society, 1946) (oversize) (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Five demonstration posters of the Ptolemaic and Copernican versions of the solar system (evidently derived from Polanyi's chapter, "Science and Reality," in Science, Faith and Society, 1946) (oversize) (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Five demonstration posters of the Ptolemaic and Copernican versions of the solar system (evidently derived from Polanyi's chapter, "Science and Reality," in Science, Faith and Society, 1946) (oversize) (Box 60, Folder 5)